dietsinreview.com 2012-06-22

# Privacy Policy - DietsInReview.com

## Mission 

To provide constructive information and education by health professionals that the public can use to implement healthy changes, support weight loss efforts and inspire to live a healthier life. 

## Privacy Policy 

The purpose of this DietsInReview.com ("the Site") privacy policy (the Policy) is to help you understand what kinds of information we may collect about you when you visit the Site, how we may use that information, whether we will disclose it, and how you can correct the information. Please note that by using the Site, you signify your agreement with the Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of the Policy, please do not use the Site. Your continued use of the Site after any changes to the Policy will mean that you have accepted the changes; therefore please bookmark this page and review it frequently. If we decide to change the Policy, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we gather, how we might use that information, and whether we will disclose it. 

Please note that the Policy applies only to the Site, and not to other websites to which we link, or to advertisers on the Site. Your use of the Site is governed by DietsInReview.com’s Terms of Service and by other published rules pertaining to particular products and services offered throughout the Site. 

## Children’s Information 

The Site is not directed toward children under thirteen years of age. DietsInReview.com does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under thirteen years of age. If you are under thirteen years of age, you should not provide any personally identifiable information through the Site. 

## The Information We Gather 

DietsInReview.com collects information from you at several different points on the Site in the manner set forth below. Whenever we collect personal information, we will make an effort to include a link to the Policy on that page. 

DietsInReview.com uses information obtained from users as stated in this Policy. DietsInReview.com does not rent, sell, or share personal information about you with other people or non-affiliated companies except to provide products or services you have requested, when we have your permission, or under the following circumstances: 

  * We provide the information to DietsInReview.com’s partners who work on behalf of or with DietsInReview.com under confidentiality agreements. These companies may use your personal information to help DietsInReview.com or its partners to communicate with you about offers from DietsInReview.com and our marketing partners. However, these companies do not have any independent right to share this information with other parties;
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, or to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims;
  * We believe it is necessary to share information in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of DietsInReview.com’s terms of use, or as otherwise required by law. 

To manage how DietsInReview.com can communicate with you, please visit [http://www.DietsInReview.com/users/account_settings](http://www.dietsinreview.com/users/account_settings)

## Disclosure of Personal Information in the Event of Merger or Sale of Assets 

DietsInReview.com, or its related entites, could merge with or be acquired by another business entity, or all or substantially all of their respective assets could be acquired. Should such a combination, acquisition or transaction occur, you should expect that DietsInReview.com would share some or all of your personal information with the acquiring or merged entity to continue serving you and other users of the Site. 

## MyDIR Community

In order to complete a user profile for MyDIR, the DietsInReview.com user community, or the MyDIR Weight Loss Tracker, a user must provide a limited amount of personal information. This includes, but is not limited to, your height, weight, desired weight goals, gender, age, first and last names, mailing address, Twitter account, personal Web site URL, e-mail address. Users have the option to make some of this information public and private. 

An internal messaging system will be used by members to communicate with one another. While an email will be sent to your personal email address (the one used to establish your MyDIR account) to notify of a new MyDIR message, this information is kept private and not shared with other members. 

The Site offers weekly giveaways to its MyDIR members. These names are selected randomly and the prize is mailed to the address included in the MyDIR profile.

## Send-To-A-Friend 

If you elect to use the "Send-To-A-Friend" service on the Site, we will ask for your friend’s name(s) and e-mail address(es). DietsInReview.com will automatically send a one-time e-mail inviting your friend(s) to visit the Site. We will store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time e-mail. 

## User Ratings and Reviews 

We provide a service that allows users to add their own ratings and reviews to our content. Please note that the reviews or any other information you provide that is placed on the Site will be available for any user to read, and is therefore no longer private. By selecting the thumbs-up or thumbs-down rating buttons a percentage of preference is calculated. This rating number is completely driven by user input and is not editable or influenced by any other source. 

DietsInReview.com owns the rights to this content and reserves the right to publish such reviews in other media formats, in its sole discretion. These user-submitted reviews are not the opinion of DietsInReview.com. 

## Community Moderation

DietsInReview.com moderates each comment and rating posted by a user on the Site to uphold the integrity of the site and ensure the safety of our users. Comments are edited to remove foul language, Web URLs and email addresses. HTML links are not permitted in comments on the Site. All comments posted on the site become the property of DietsInReview.com.

## Advertising Policy 

DietsInReview.com is funded by advertisers. It is the policy of DietsInReview.com to accept and place these advertisements via banners and text links throughout the Web site. DietsInReview.com maintains a constructive and unbiased position and does not allow advertisers to have any editorial influence. Advertisements on DietsInReview.com are clearly indicated with an "advertisement" message. 

The "Start this Diet Now" button can also be a source of advertising dollars for DietsInReview.com. This button is included for the reader's convenience, to quickly access the diet program or weight loss product that interests them. Often times this link directs users to the same or similar product's site and DietsInReview.com receives revenue based on actions taken there. 

DietsInReview.com accepts advertisements from direct relationships, third-party advertisers, and from advertising networks, which serve ads to the site. Advertisements displayed on DietsInReview.com may be provided through an ad server or ad network. These ads are not endorsed by DietsInReview.com, but do provide funding to the site. 

It is the policy of DietsInReview.com not to share your personally identifiable information with these advertisers without prior consent. Once you've engaged with one of these advertisers, you'll need to consult their individual privacy policies to learn about their practices. 

Opt-Out: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>

## Cobranded and Other Affiliated Sites

Certain information or services offered or provided on or through the Site from time to time may be provided on or through other sites operated by or in conjunction with third party providers (“Partners”). These sites may have the same “look and feel” of the Site, and are often cobranded, such that a Partner’s logo or name may appear on the site, or the Partner’s name may appear in the URL. Aggregate or personally identifiable information collected about you on these sites may be shared by DietsInReview.com with that Partner. A Partner will not rent, sell, or disclose any of your personally identifiable information to third parties unless you consent to its doing so, for example, by opting-in while on a particular site to receive information or offers from a Partner’s affiliates, partners, or other third parties. 

## Third Party Links and Member Websites

You acknowledge that we do not monitor, control or endorse the information collection or privacy practices of any third parties, any cobranded or other affiliated sites which may or may not be owned or operated by or in conjunction with DietsInReview.com, or any credit card order processors, product shippers or other third parties who provide services throughout the Site. Accordingly, DietsInReview.com assumes no liability or responsibility for the information collection and privacy practices of any third party. In addition, DietsInReview.com is not responsible for the content of any third party websites, including a third party’s use of any cookies or any other information (such as IP address, browser type or operating system) collected when you "click-through" links to their sites or view advertisements served by them. Even though certain information collected by such third parties might not identify you personally, we strongly encourage you to become familiar with their privacy practices, and to contact such third parties if you have any questions about their respective privacy policies. 

In addition, the Site may provide links to other Internet websites or resources ("Linked Sites"). DietsInReview.com neither controls nor endorses such Linked Sites nor have we reviewed or approved any content that appears on such Linked Sites. You acknowledge and agree that DietsInReview.com is not responsible for the legality, accuracy or inappropriate nature of any content, advertising, products or other materials on or available from such Linked Sites. You further acknowledge and agree that DietsInReview.com shall not be responsible or liable, directly or indirectly, for any damage or loss caused or alleged to be caused by or in connection with use of or reliance on any such content, goods, and services available on or through any such Linked Site. 

## Review Process

DietsInReview.com employs a team of health and nutrition professionals to conduct each review published on the Site. These reviews are written in good faith that all information is accurate to the best of our knowledge. When physical reviews cannot be completed, extensive research is conducted to capture a thorough representation of the product, its benefits and disadvantages. The reviews published on the Site are the unbiased, objective opinion of DietsInReview.com. Our reviews are never influenced by third parties or advertisers, and we do not publish sponsored reviews. We aim to present the facts about a product or service and allow the user to form their own opinion. 

## Security

The Site uses reasonable security methods to protect the data that resides on our servers. However, no security system is impenetrable. DietsInReview.com cannot warrant or guarantee the security of its servers, nor can it guarantee that information that users supply will not be intercepted while being transmitted to DietsInReview.com over the Internet. If we ever ask users to enter credit card numbers, that information shall always be encrypted. 

## How To Contact Us

Should you have any questions or concerns about the Policy, please send an e-mail to [help@dietsinreview.com](mailto:help@dietsinreview.com).
